

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# NATHAN HAMILTON

# **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: 615-604-8814

Email: nathan.a.hamilton@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathan-hamilton-3864b520

Github: https://github.com/nathanRomad

## PERSONAL PROFILE

A world traveler, business manager, and software developer with an insatiable intellectual curiosity, passion for problem solving, as well as highly detail oriented. I am ready to put years of operations experience to work as a leader in softeware development.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Hands-on SQL experience
- Javascript, HTML, CSS, REACT, Python and Django experience.
- · Git and Github processes.
- · SQLite and JSON Server
- · Operations management

# **OTHER SKILLS**

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design and implement database structures
- · Highly Detail oriented
- · Project Management and Leadership

## **EDUCATION**

# TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY (TSU) - NASHVILLE, TN

B.B.A in Economics & Finance Golden Key National Honor Society/Beta Gamma Sigma - GPA: 3.6

Emphasis: International Business (first TSU candidate for degree)

2012

#### CENTER OF ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE IN INTELLIGENCE STUDIES

Tianjin; Shanghai; Beijing China 2011

Concentration on economic relations and the emphasis to the local level economy and businesses.

## UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE - CAMP CASEY AIN/DONGDUCHEON, SOUTH KOREA

Credit courses while serving active military duty- Comprehensive curriculum 2004-2005

# **PROJECTS**

## topFIVE | Mar 2021

- · Full-stack one page application for keeping track of your topFIVE's!
- · This application will allow a user to log in and create, read, update, or delete their topFIVE's.
- A user will be able to 'follow' other users topFIVE's.

## **HOLIDAY ROAD - ACCIDENTAL ENGINE**

- Creating wireframes and Dependency diagrams
- Incorporating Agile framework and methodologies
- Technologies used; javascript, html and css, API's.

# **HELLO WORLD - TRAVEL COMPANY**

This was our first group project at Nashville Software School, and we used HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript, Event Listeners, Git, Github, and http-server to build the website.

# NATHAN HAMILTON

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2021 - Present

- · 6 month Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React, Python, Django
- · Git & Github codebase & task management
- · Collaborative coding & solo app development

## **RESTAURANT MANAGER**

Henley Nashville | 2019 -2021

- · Recruiting, training and supervising staff.
- · Managing budgets, ordering supplies, managing inventory
- ensuring compliance with licensing, hygiene and health and safety legislation/guidelines.

#### **GENERAL MANAGER / CONSULTANT**

Never Never | 2019

- · Build and Launch successful bar program
- Ordering, scheduling, creating Standard Operating Procedures (SOP's)

#### **LEAD BARTENDER**

Hemingway's Bar & Hideaway | 2017-2019

- Prepare cocktails, replenish stock, maintain equipment, improve business efficiencies.
- Responsible for training incoming bar staff

#### Team Member - Marketing

Bernard Health | 2017

- Develop and qualify new sales opportunities. Schedule product demos & discovery calls for account executives.
- Utilize effective email and telephone communication techniques. Maintain prospect and client records database.

#### **Operations Manager**

Park Nashville | 2016

- Manage operations of daily tasks, build and keep up the schedule, payroll, time-punches, and material management for more than a dozen accounts and personnel of 65+.
- Preserve positive relationships with clients while maintaining high level results in a fast paced and ever changing environment.
  M\*Street main account.

#### **Fuel Operator**

Pacific Architects and Engineers (PAE) - McMurdo Station, Antarctica | 2012-2013 & 2014-2015

- · Provide assistance to all grantees and other agencies in support of National Science Foundation objectives.
- Perform fuel transfers, aircraft refueling, fuel testing, maintenance and operation of fuels facilities for McMurdo Station and remote field stations.